Welcome to our bonus Q&A on plot web
exclusive um you have some excellent
questions we touch on digging deeper
into plot archetypes and Frameworks we
uh touch on video games and writing for
video games uh kind of briefly we talk
about layering conflicts uh and we dig
into why does dune work when Paul trades
really never fails at anything he tries
so enjoy this uh companion uh Q&A
session on plot to my lecture series I
hope you enjoy it uh this is our Q&A um
on plot with questions from YouTube
right here in my hand um as our our
bonus for you thank you for uh including
all of these questions for us I've got
eight of them here that I'm going to go
through and uh we'll see where we are at
that point so uh my question is how do
you write effectively how do you
effectively write a betrayal Arc how do
you make it hit hard and resonate with
the audience and how do you make the
falling out feel realistic without
drawing too much attention to it I like
my main character to not realize it's
happening until it's too late um so
making a betrayal Arc work really well
is probably going to involve writing a
relationship plot but then having it go
wrong and I maybe didn't emphasize this
enough in my in my original lectures all
of the different sort of plot arcs can
go wrong they can turn sour in some way
for instance you can have a an arc that
is built around an information Arc a
mystery where the characters come to the
wrong conclusion and then there are
problems after the fact um you can have
a relationship Arc where people start
off really well match to each other and
if it's not a ro romance it's a betrayal
Arc uh between two friends you show how
these characters work well together uh
and then instead of braiding the Roses
you have those Roses keep stabbing each
other you show how their motivations are
diverging right and how um it's um it's
turning sour because they keep running a
foul of each other instead of helping
each other and if it's going to be a
character kind of turning on the
protagonist you show that they're
getting more and more
disgruntled you really want the ear part
therefore to show how good they are
together like in this sort of Arc you've
maybe even skipped some of the getting
to know each other so that they are
already you're starting the book with
these are two friends and you hit hard
why they work well together you can
Coast a long ways on that if you do it
well readers will assume that they're
best friends and will even as those
cracks start to appear will ignore them
because they are such good best friends
particularly remember your reader will
follow the character's attention so if
the primary character is still thinking
about their friend as a very good friend
it will cover up the actual actions
which are the show that these things are
going worse and worse uh until that
betrayal happens and then just make sure
that your motivations really make sense
the reason that someone would turn they
would turn against each other that
they've got a solid reason that that
you're like I should have seen that it
work like to basically other twist
you're foreshadowing that it's a
relationship plot that they're getting
along but then behind the scenes you are
actually breaking that so when it
happens it's surprising yet
inevitable that is my recommendation on
that one question how do you balance uh
and promise Bittersweet endings um I
would recommend that uh if you're
shooting for Bittersweet that your story
makes it clear early on that these are
this is the sort of world where things
don't always turn out exactly as you
want them to as the reader might um and
you do this in a lot of different ways
you show that life is pretty hard in
this place you show that friends have
died in the past or that there are
casualties in the the middle of the book
um you make sure that you know you're
focused on some accomplishments and some
failures that feels very realistic uh
when these sorts of sorts of things
happen I think that the balance um
really comes down to for me often times
I'm watching my Beta readers a lot with
this I'm watching and saying all right
how much of the bitter is coming through
how much of the sweet is coming through
do I need to change that balance in any
way or am I pleased with how that
balance is um I find that as long as the
personal accomplishment of the
characters have happened like theyve
achieved something uh personally U if
they've made progress people tend to
take those as more sweet than bitter
meaning if they fail in the main capital
P plot but in the lowercase p they've
grown and become a better person uh we
tend to be pretty cool with that um the
reverse still can work but those tend to
feel more bitter than sweet um when the
character has accomplished the big p
plot um but it has cost them personally
so an example of this Lord of the Rings
ending is Bittersweet the capital P plot
has been accomplished but froto is
basically destroyed as a person um and
that really the bitter comes out uh
really powerfully in that uh
particularly in the films where they
Cuts things like the scouring and things
like that so you're just left with Frodo
can't live a normal life anymore and
you'll notice how that feels triumphant
but very bitter the reverse in the sort
of uh Hollywood thing where it's like I
accomplished my own personal goals but I
die achieving the capital P those tend
to feel very triumphant um even though
the character has died um because they
have fulfilled their kind of personal
motives and things like that uh their
character Arc has come to fruition those
feel much more triumphant than bitter uh
just in my experience so that might help
you with balancing how those work you
can of course make uh either of those
types of endings have more bitter or
more sweet depending can I talk about
layering conflict more uh which is say
giving the POV character both internal
and external conflict in a scene and
blending those conflicts to create
something even more Dynamic and
satisfying sure uh this is one of my
favorite things to do so I'm happy to
talk about this one I love it when
stories to this I love uh doing it in my
own stories uh this comes with a good
sign posting right early on making the
promises and showing this is what the
character is doing and then making sure
you're showing that progress along the
way and often with a good character Arc
you're going to have some serious
failures in there and we'll talk about
characters uh in coming weeks but the
idea with a good you know character Arc
is you need to show why this is
legitimately a flaw why it's
legitimately something that they need to
work on or work around uh why you know
they handicap the flaw or um the you
know the problems that they're dealing
with um and you want to make sure that
we understand what is supposed to be
triumphant about that um going back to
Star Wars which is the the kind of er
example that I use a lot because uh so
many people have seen it we do get to
see Luke Get Zapped uh by the the thing
unable to trust in the force quite yet
um before we see him be triumphantly
accepting and embracing his Destiny we
get to see ob1 say you need to learn the
ways of the force just at the beginning
as your promise Luke is going to learn
the ways of the force and this is
relevant to his story um you get to see
that Luke isn't enough to face Darth
Vader yet and that ob1 is going to have
to die uh in order to protect him
because he's not ready for that
challenge yet all of these things build
to Luke taking that first step to become
a Jedi at the end of uh the first movie
and what makes that really satisfying is
we have already set up in that same
scene with your promises that shooting
um you know down the tube without the
force is really really difficult and oh
it didn't go in it didn't work you need
that extra boost um I always like to
make sure that I'm doing a little bit of
each of these things periodically
through my story that I'm not just
batching it all and being like here
we're doing all the character stuff and
then we're done with that we're moving
on uh I like to move it through and seat
it and one of the nice things you can do
with with this is the character flaw the
character handicap um the things they're
working on the internal conflict uh
whether again it's something that they
need to change or something they just
need to learn to work with um is causing
the conflict through the middle of the
story The Challenge in this is you don't
want us to we don't want to make us
dislike the character and that's I would
say your big challenge in this uh
sometimes that happens where um you get
really frustrated the character because
they have this flaw that seems like
you're like just deal with it and this
comes down to making sure that we
understand and like the character and
understand why this flaw exists and you
relate it to something very human that
we all have um and so that when this
character you know is too shy to do what
they need to do and that's you know the
thing that they're working on or whether
whatever it is um when that moment
happens uh and there is failure because
of it causing further complication and
conflict that as a author we are quick
to have them acknowledge I need to get
over this I can't keep letting this
stand in my way um and or at least
having the narrative recognize that to
to let us know to hang that Lantern on
yes this character is working on this
this is really important you should be a
little frustrated but do try to be
understanding so that when it does kind
of come to fruition at the end it's a
standup and sharance moment um that said
once again you can have them just never
get over it uh people will get
frustrated with the character but in
that case you kind of lean into other
reasons that people would like the
character because a little frustration
can be a good thing uh watch my
character lecture that's uh that's
coming up very soon we'll we'll talk
about those ideas so um and really try
to hit those beats and try to give us a
onew punch at the end where your plot
structure comes together and often times
you kind of want to set it up so the
some big problem that the character's
flaw caused is going to happen again and
it'll be an even bigger problem and this
time they get over it Luke not being
able to you know block the the
lightsaber thing the little bols of the
livesaver he gets stung on the ankle but
now if he doesn't trust the force um the
entire Rebel faction is going to get
blown up uh the stakes are bigger he
can't afford to fail this time uh but
fortunately he's been learning learning
and paying attention and he gets that
little push from Obi-Wan and he decides
to trust and it's kind of that for Luke
it's that step into the darkness being
willing to hope that that he will be
able to walk forward through darkness
and find his way anyway in your lectures
on plot you use a lot of good examples
but I notice a lot of them come from
movies hey uh my question is what plot
elements should we as writers take into
account that maybe movies don't what are
the Ben benefits of the written word
when it comes specifically to plotting
yeah what an excellent question uh I do
use movies a lot because they um they
tend to be people have watched them more
uh you know you can you can count on
people watching them that they they take
two hours instead of 10 to 50 hours um
and beyond that they do have to condense
all of the stuff so they tend to hit the
beats in more clear ways books have a
lot more space but that is to your
advantage so a couple of things that
books do better than film number one
being inside a character's head either
through a first person or third person
limited or even an omniscient gives you
so many advantages you can use it too
much you can do what we call Naval
gazing where pages and Pages pass of
just the character ruminating on things
and we're all guilty of this in writing
because it is one of the strengths of
writing that you immediately get to see
what the character feels and thinks
about his situation that immediately
helps us connect to the character in
ways you know in film they have to Luke
has to look wistfully up at the passing
the the Sun
and think man I wish that you know I
could I could go out in those Stars he
can't can't hear him think that in Dune
you can hear Paul atres thinking about
um why you know the dangers of Dune and
how he misses his home planet and all of
these things he you're right there in
his head and you can see it and that can
create an instant sort of connection
there um books um we have a lot more
space to play with and this allows us to
do more of this or to have more scenes
reinforcing the same ideas uh in film
you have three hours at most most films
two hours uh some 90 minutes so you got
to hit those beats hard and you got to
hit them kind of obviously uh in books
you can Slow Burn on some of these
things you can have more failures you
can have more steps backward and when
you do the one step backward two steps
forward sort of things um there is so
much that you can do that doesn't have
to um relate directly to any these
things you can use more time on Side
characters if you want so space and
Viewpoint are two big ones um that uh
that are advantages uh to books um and
then I would say an advantage to books
is also a disadvantage wrapped up in one
that is that there aren't visuals to go
along with it and so you can count on
the reader to fill in blanks for you in
fact you have to uh that makes the
reader participatory in the practice in
a way that film they're more of an
observer in a book they're more of a
participant um and by you can in your
stories make use of this by using fine
brush Strokes um or sorry broad brush
Strokes to paint characters um and say
you know give one identifying feature
and let the reader fill in the rest if
that's the way that you want to tell
your stories um you just have a lot of
flexibility in the way you use voice and
things like that so we will try to get a
lecture on voice but there's uh there's
two things um you ask specifically what
the benefits are when it comes to
plotting specifically it is that you can
do more you can have more failures you
can have more successes you can Meander
more and get there it lets you have more
red herrings and it lets you have twists
be in some ways more spectacular because
there's just so much more going on in a
book how does what is being taught
translate to writing for video games
what to look out for when watching your
lectures what are some good examples of
writing that can be found in video games
so video games um are such a huge topic
it is difficult to talk about uh in
reference to plot specifically because
plot is one of the places where video
games are by necessity putting the
player in control um a lot of the the
best examples of Storytelling in um in
video games are when the player gets to
make some big decision that has huge
ramifications on the story um otherwise
a lot of the best storytelling in video
games it kind of there's like a
Continuum right on one side you have uh
only doing environmental storytelling
right like um like Elden ring likes to
do where there the story is only how you
piece it together and engage with it as
you're getting it through little bits of
lore and then all the way over here we
have the uh the genres affectionately
called Walking simulators where you're
walking through a movie that is
happening uh the interactive elements
are kind of moved um to the a back seat
and really a lot of walking simulators
your um your ability to influence the
plot is really kind of minimal what you
get influen is how quickly you move
through it uh and things like that like
the the the famous One which isn't
walking the famous VR one where the
story plays out every time you blink it
changes scenes and so you keep your eyes
open long enough to experience a scene
but then occasionally you blink and that
scene ends um you know that's that's
something that no other genre could do
but you can see how your control um as a
player over that is only in minimal in
what how you blink but that becomes the
whole mechanic it's really brilliant um
so what how does what I'm talking about
Translate to video games I would focus
on what are your payoffs for your story
like what what kind of experience is
your payoff in the video game something
like in uh Mass Effect where you have
this huge payoff in that you're going to
make a decision at the end of the story
that is going to have deep ramifications
for this team of people that you've come
to love that you've built over time is
that your big moment where the player
valtion has an effect and how can you
then earn that that in Mass Effect they
earn it by making sure that you love all
the side characters so that when you're
making big decisions about how their
lives might play out then um you care
because you like them all um and so um
interweaving narrative plot and game
mechanics would be my number one
recommendation for how you make a video
game plot uh work and interesting um I
like how a lot of video games kind of
start with with game mechanics and then
design storytelling to match the game
mechanics this is just something that
you would think is not very cool you're
not putting the story in the Forefront
but I think it actually is really cool
for video games an example of this would
be where um video games make your death
diagetic such as in Borderlands uh right
Borderlands they have a a machine that
brings people back to life uh and this
machine brings you back to life and
charges you money for resurrecting you
and it becomes a a a way that jokes are
really fun uh the second game which is
the strongest has a scene where the bad
guy pays you to to to go jump off a
cliff um knowing you'll get you'll
you'll come back to life but he just
wants to see if you'll do it and he
makes fun of you the whole way uh you
get a quest to jump off a cliff and then
he's like I can't believe you did that
here's your money um it's really funny
it's really morbid um it plays into the
game mechanics uh and things like that
and so I like when that happens of
course the big problem Borderlands then
has is the same problem that Final
Fantasy has which is it sometimes likes
to kill characters and cut scenes in a
world where death has been proven to be
um not a a permanent thing and then
suddenly it is in this one instance for
reasons that are just narrative um and
that always bugs me in video games so um
there you are there's some rants on
video games and plot if you are going to
make a big important cut scene where a
character dies permanently um you know
come up with a reason why they can't
just be resurrected by a phoenix down um
that you have 99 of in your you can tell
it's only been how many years it's only
been 20 plus years uh since that
happened I'm like I got 99 of these
things this is the character I leveled
up the most you are totally ruining my
party um yes they got stabbed but I mean
I have healing potions I'm standing
right there so yeah uh you've been
talking a lot about plot structure and I
like what you said about uh tragedies
often using a hero's journey where the
hero never takes the final step I was
also thinking about tragedies but this
applies to any story is there a case
where you want to use try succeed Cycles
instead of try fail Cycles uh so when I
say try fail Cycles yeah I think you get
I we'll get if so what stories does and
what stories does that work for example
in Dune especially in the movie part two
Paul succeeds at every attempt he makes
to get what he wants somehow the uh plot
continues to build um yes um excellent
so why does dune work let's an analyze
this why does dune work Paul succeeds at
every Point except the big one at the
beginning uh spoilers for Dune um at the
beginning
um Paul is incapable of saving his
father and gets exiled Out Among the
fman um he then has a series of huge
successes until he succeeds at the end
so there's a couple things going on with
Paul and that you are playing into
exactly you've noticed um spoilers Dune
is a tragedy not right uh the story of
Dune is Paul resist ing becoming like
the har Conan in order to bring down the
har Conan and he fails right he gets
leaves the you know the life that he he
thinks that he wants being a good person
and he instead Builds an army bent on
Vengeance and unleashes them upon the
Galaxy in order to get his revenge the
story of Dune is the story of of Paul's
downfall so on one hand we have
plot-wise he is succeeding but we learn
that we don't want to it's that whole
giving someone a promising someone a car
but giving them an airplane right at the
end we realize we didn't want Paul to
succeed in all this he's become um a
villain through doing this uh and he's
more complex than that that's why Dune
is so great but you have this huge
failure at the beginning you give us
what you think you want which is Revenge
and then you show us through the the
course of the the rest of the story that
we probably shouldn't have wanted that
that the freman are overly brutal um and
uh unleashing them as you have um is a
terrible solution to a terrible problem
and maybe there was no better solution
but it's still terrible and that's
heartbreaking um and so why do I think
works is because of that you are slowly
coming to realize that you are not
watching the hero origin story you're
watching a villain's origin story and
it's just really subtle uh and
brilliantly accomplished um and you know
showing him resist uh trying to use the
benzar um you know manipulation of the
fman and eventually deciding I am going
to be their Prophet even though I know
that I'm not actually the prophet I am
that this is all made up I am still
going to manipulate their religion in
order to get what I want um this is it
it's it's really a kind of a master
class and how to do this specific thing
um and it's very dangerous to attempt
but uh if you do it well it makes you
stand out very well so yes you would say
the try succeed cycle in this case it
works because Paul is trying and
succeeding but the the kind of hidden
plot is you realize that you don't want
him to um by the end of it um but let's
point out that you can do it in other
ways a another common example I would
say of a triced
cycle um is let's use Dirk pit let's use
a book example um Dirk pit the book
series uh if you haven't read it there
was one movie it was called Sahara it
was actually a really good movie but it
came out at the wrong time right around
911 um and so I do recommend you you
watch it it has as um the rift tracks
people say uh the world's most shirtless
man Matthew mccon uh in a very good role
um and um it's a it's it's a good
adaptation of the Dirk pit novels what
are the Dirk pit novels the Dirk pit
novels are all about watching competent
people be extra competent um we as as
readers competence is one of the things
that draws us to people and uh you'll
see in my lectures coming up on
character that there is a danger in this
in that we sometimes bond to villains
because they are so competent when the
heroes are kind of you know Meandering
their way through learning to be
competent uh but we really like
competence and sometimes some books are
built around the idea of a highly
competent character facing only external
conflicts and largely succeeding on them
why does this work well if you make the
problem big enough and the threats
dangerous enough if at any point failure
leads to death and destruction and the
stakes are high and tense and the
competence is played very competently
Dune does this as as well you won't mind
that they're succeeding at every point
because the author is making the M
stakes and the dangers and the
difficulty of what's being accomplished
so very dire at all turns that you're on
the edge of your seat wondering if this
is the time that the person will fall um
you know when you're watching traes uh
you know the Highwire act they will play
it up like because you know they're not
going to fall they never fall but you
always wonder if they will and that's
the question um for some of for some of
these acts and that's that works very
well Dirk pit is all about Dirk pit
being awesome um he is awesome at every
term and he rarely fails in anything and
they're very readable um and so it is a
good question to ask those are two very
good book examples of how you can have
something that is try succeed rather
than try fail um you will often find in
these books that a character will
succeed But realize that the scope of
what they need to succeed in is that now
gotten great grer I've done this thing
froto has gotten the ring to Rivendell
but then
realizes no I need to go further uh this
was only the Prelude and you know froto
does succeed in that there's not a
failure and there's a bunch of near
failures but there's no failures in
getting that ring to rivendel but then
he realizes it needs to go um much much
further and that expansion of scope is
another way to help with the kind of try
succeed cycle uh what an excellent
question um uh really some great
analysis on that one can Brandon talk
about plot archetypes he mentioned how
Miss born is an interplay of heist
Master Apprentice mystery and romance uh
how do you use plot archetypes and how
to pick original combination uh
excellent question so this is only one
of the this is only one of the ways you
can tell the story um but I would often
say that what works best for plot
archetypes is to watch or read a bunch
of them uh and distill them down to
different different types and subtypes
and what you like about them um you know
mistborn is a heist but I identified
when I was working on Mporn two very
different structures of heists um there
is the type of heist where the
characters are working hard on this big
problem pulling off this Heist and they
get to the end and then everything gets
thrown out the window by a giant
disruption uh the Italian job um if you
want to watch the new one excellent
Heist movie that follows this uh and
then the characters use the resources
that they've done through the first part
of the heist in order to uh solve the
problem um so you none of this middle
space is wasted you're just using again
but there's another type of heist Oceans
11 is one of these where they plot a
really difficult problem and then they
execute excellently on their plan at the
end even if there's a few little
problems in it mostly it's just their
complications than what they've planned
and they pull it off brilliantly um and
in that you just get to watch the plan
unfold and how much fun it is you'll
notice in Oceans 11 um they make sure to
use a character who's not completely in
the not to help create some tension in
the climax uh where you think things are
going wrong but it was the plan all
along um but identifying the different
types the different elements what works
best for your story and what doesn't is
uh one thing that I would do um novels
should generally have multiples of these
exciting which one relates more to your
character arcs which one relates more to
your cap what is your capital P um what
is the big Stakes of this story um
spoilers for mbor um but mistborn turns
from a heist uh into a one of your
classic sort of Revolution narratives um
by the end uh and the the big thing that
makes um it's it's using kind of the
structure of uh The Italian Job but when
things go wrong it Chang es to a new
plot um it expands the scope and says no
we're not here to just Rob the world
we're here to save the world um and that
transition between tropes is uh is also
what makes uh knives out so brilliant um
where it transitions from who it to cat
and mouse mystery which are two
different types of mystery um Knives Out
is another excellent example H done it
is the mystery where it's like you're
trying to figure out who was behind this
cat and mouse is where you have a
protagonist who is the villain who is
trying to stay away from the cat who is
chasing them uh and it can be told
either way but the fugitive is the
classic example of cat and mouse where
it is a kind of who done it mystery with
a cat and mouse on top of it where he's
trying to figure out who the one arm man
is but really the story the capital P
plot is can he stay away from Tommy Lee
Jones um and knives out does the same
thing uh no not giving spoilers um but
Midway through you find out who did it
and then we shift to their perspective
as they try to stay ahead of the
detective uh being able to to modulate
and switch between these things is what
a chef does right knowing that you can
take some elements and you can build
toward another and you can layer them uh
un underneath each other you can take a
relationship plot and that you can twist
it into a betrayal plot um as another
question asked this is the sort of
things that I would like you as students
to be practicing and learning and paying
attention to um and so how do you find
the combinations try them swapping
genres helps a lot um mixing and
matching and just trying and seeing what
works uh you know mistborn is my second
attempt at mistborn the one that you
have read uh and the F first one um
didn't work so well um and so sometimes
you just need to you need to fail a few
times you need to have your own trifil
Cycles before you can have your succeed
Cycles I have a question about the scale
of plot almost any story can be expanded
on
expanded or shrunk massively by removing
or adding characters plot lines mini
arcs and so on for example without the
existence Saron it might be possible to
take a few hundred Pages uh less time
for the good guys to win um this also
especially extends how many PS you tell
in your story so how do you know how
much how do I know how much I should ex
expand my story or more importantly how
much should I shrink it how do I know
what scale my story should be for the
best end result uh excellent question um
so part of this is based on how much
space you have are you writing a short
story a Nolla or a novel as a newer
writer your answer might be I don't know
Brandon um well practice will get you
there you'll start to learn how long it
will take you to tell a story um
usually professional writers myself
included can tell from our outline um
sometimes as we're writing the book and
we get a certain way through the outline
or a certain way through the gut
instinct if you're writing as a
discovery writer we're like
no it's going to take me longer um I'm
going to have to expand the scope of
what I'm doing um here's some rules of
thumb for you if you're going over
around 120,000 words the reader is going
to expect an escalation in scope it's
hard to go over 120,000 words and make
it feel like it's still a small scale
story that's why most Thrillers most
romances um these things they stay
sometimes in the 80 to 100,000 word not
saying you can't do it um but you'll
notice as Harry Potter gets longer and
longer the scope expands it's no longer
can I can I you know get good enough
grades to remain a wizard it is can I
save the world and uh long books people
tend to expect long scope now that can
be scope in saving the world it can
instead be a lot of historical instead
make the scope about following an entire
family across Generations or an entire
life time um that's an you know that's
that type of scope of just you know
generational or one person's entire life
uh but you you want to give that weight
uh to some of it if you're going to be
going longer than about 120 particularly
150 right uh some rules of thumb like
Dune is I think 170 to 180 uh Lord of
the Rings Al together is like 300
something so Lord of the Rings uh we
just looked it up around 480 so 150 per
book um is giving you kind of that that
sort of Epic scope um but on contrast um
technically Christmas Carol is a Nolla
it's not even a full novel um it's about
one person's life hit very quickly just
going to depend on what if you can give
the weight that people are expecting for
that length of a sitdown do understand
one of the big shifts that happens here
and why uh this happens with people is
that um a book in the 80 to 100 range a
person can conceivably read in one day a
lot of the faster readers they'll read
that in five to eight hours um and the
fast readers like they'll sit down and
that's one sitting it's why a lot of
Thrillers are in that range where it's
like you can pull someone through kind
of buy their you know their teeth grab
them and just yank them through this
story to the end that they're like
gasping and a lot of romance novels are
doing that gasp are just a different
variety um and they're just pulling you
through this story real fast right um
whereas an epic story people are putting
this book down and so it's a they have
to digest this book across days or
sometimes months uh and you have to
build your plot based around the idea
that this is going to have break points
people are going to sit down they're
going to enjoy and immerse them
themselves in the world but they're not
going to read it in one sitting and that
changes how people experience the
stories and that experiences how that
changes how you should be plotting and
pacing um I shoot for big long chapters
in storm life that when they're done you
have had a complete sort of story be
told um and you feel fine tell putting
that book down for a while unless it's
at a climactic moment where I'm cutting
faster with shorter chapters so that
it's pulling you through because short
chapters actually pull people through
faster than long chapters do so um
there's um there's some of that uh
excellent questions um very well done um
I'm going to do another one of these for
you um with character so be preparing
your questions watch the the the
upcoming lectures on character and then
uh we'll do another web exclusive I hope
this was useful to you uh thank you so
much let us know in the comments if this
format works for you